Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Domestic Advertisements, part 1, 1875-2001 and undated, bulk 1920s-1990s RL.00687
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Main Files Series, 1875-2001 and undated
  - Ford Motor Co., 1931-1998
    - Ford Motor Co. Addition 2004-0010 (Box FM50)
      - 1992-1993 (Box FM53)
        - 1992
          - Explorer, F-Series truck, vans (Box FM53)
          - Probe (Box FM53)
          - Tempo (Box FM53)
        - 1993
          - Aspire (Box FM53)
          - Commercial trucks (Box FM53)
          - Corporate, racing (Box FM53)
          - Econoline van, Club Wagon (Box FM53)
          - Escort (Box FM53)
          - F-Series truck (Box FM53)
          - Mustang, Thunderbird (Box FM53)
          - Ranger (Box FM53)
      - 1994-1995 (Box FM54)
        - 1994
          - Aspire (Box FM54)
          - Explorer, F-Series truck (Box FM54)
          - Ranger (Box FM54)
          - Windstar (Box FM54)
        - 1994-1995
          - Commercial trucks (Box FM54)
          - Contour, Escort, Probe (Box FM54)
          - Corporate (Box FM54)
          - Mustang (Box FM54)
          - Racing (Box FM54)
          - Taurus (Box FM54)
        - 1995
          - Explorer, F-Series truck (Box FM54)
      - 1996-2001 (Box FM55)
        - 1996, Commercial trucks and vehicles (Box FM55)
        - 1996-1998
          - Corporate, general, racing (Box FM55)
          - Vans (Box FM55)
        - 1996-2000
          - Cars: Contour, Escort, Mustang, Taurus, Thunderbird (Box FM55)
          - F-Series truck (Box FM55)
          - Ranger (Box FM55)
        - 1996-2001, Explorer (Box FM55)
        - 1997-2001, Expedition (Box FM55)
        - 1998, Ecostar (Box FM55)
        - 1999, Excursion (Box FM55)
        - 1999-2001, Focus (Box FM55)
        - 2000, Escape (Box FM55)
      - Undated outdoor advertising, ca. 1980s-1990s (Box FM56)
        - Aerostar (Box FM56)
        - Escort (Box FM56)
        - Explorer (Box FM56)
        - F-Series truck (Box FM56)
        - Mustang (Box FM56)
        - Ranger (Box FM56)
        - Taurus (Box FM56)
        - Thunderbird (Box FM56)
  - Free Europe Press: see Advertising Council (Crusade for Freedom) (Box FM56)
  - French, R.T.: see R.T. French (Box FM56)
  - Gerber, 1977-1993
    [See also Oversize Folder 20.]
    - 1977-1985 (Box GE1)
    - 1986-1993 (Box GE2)
  - Gillette, 1971-1979
    - 1971-1979 (Box GI1)
  - Goldman-Sachs, 1974-1991
    [See also Oversize Folder 21.]
    - 1974-1991 (Box GS1)
  - Goodyear, 1979-1996
    - 1979-1980, 1983-1986, 1990-1996 (Box GY1)
  - Grand Union, 1981-1982
    [See also Oversize Box OV17.]
    - 1981-1982 (Box GU1)
  - Hamm's: see Theodore Hamm Brewing Company (Box GU1)
  - Health and Tennis Corp. of America: see Bally Manufacturing Corp. (Box GU1)
  - Hyatt Hotels, Corp., 1979-1987
    For related materials see the J. Walter Thompson Co. Chicago Office, Hyatt Hotels Corp. Account Files.
    [See also Oversize Box OV18.]
    - 1979-1981 and 1980s (Box HY1)
    - 1982-1984 (Box HY2)
    - 1985-1987 (Box HY3)
  - IBM, 1982-1989
    - 1982-1989 (Box IB1)
  - Institute of Life Insurance, 1939-1975
    - 1939-1945 (Box IL1)
    - 1946-1953 (Box IL2)
    - 1954-1969, 1971, 1973-1975 (Box IL3)
  - Intercontinental Hotels, 1963-1975
    - 1963 (Box IH1)
    - 1964 (Box IH2)
    - 1965, Various locales (Box IH3)
    - 1965-1967 (Box IH4)
    - 1968, Consumer and special groups (Box IH5)
    - 1968, Corporate, various locales (Box IH6)
    - 1971-1975 (Box IH6)
    - 1969, Consumer, trade, special campaigns and openings (Box IH7)
    - 1968, Various locales (Box IH7)
  - Irving Trust, 1918-1988
    Fine line drawings, often of New York City locales, appear in the newspaper advertisements of the 1920s.
    [See also Oversize Box OV18; Oversize Folder 22.]
    - 1918-1925 (Box IT1)
    - 1926-1931 (Box IT2)
    - 1933-1942 (Box IT3)
    - 1943-1950 (Box IT4)
    - 1951-1960 (Box IT5)
    - 1961-1978 (Box IT6)
    - 1979-1988 (Box IT7)
  - JandJ Colman, 1925-1950
    - 1925-1938 (Box JC1)
    - 1928-1950, Insertion schedules (Box JC2)
    - 1939-1950 (Box JC2)
  - J.B. Williams, 1939-1969
    - 1939-1948, 1956-1962, 1969 (Box JB1)
  - Jergens: see Andrew Jergens Co. (Box JB1)
  - Johns-Manville Corp., 1948-1957
    - 1948-1950 (Box JM1)
    - 1951-1952 (Box JM2)
    - 1953-1957 (Box JM3)
  - Johnson Wax: see S.C. Johnson and Son, Inc. (Box JM3)
  - Jos. Schlitz Brewing Co., 1934-1982
    [See also Oversize Box OV19.]
    - 1934, 1956-1959 (Box JS1)
    - 1960-1961, 1978-1979 (Box JS2)
    - 1980-1982 (Box JS3)
  - Jovan, 1975-1983
    [See also Oversize Folder 23.]
    - 1975-1983 (Box JO1)
  - J. Walter Thompson Co., 1889-1990s
    House advertisements are an important source of information about company operations and philosophy.
    [See also Oversize Box OV19; Oversize Folders 24-25.]
    - 1889, 1916-1934 (photocopies) (Box JW1)
    - 1902-1903, 1906, 1916-1921 (Box JW1)
    - nd., other agency tributes (Box JW1)
    - 1921-1925 (Box JW2)
    - 1926-1931 (Box JW3)
    - 1932-1937 (Box JW4)
    - 1938-1942 (Box JW5)
    - 1943-1947 (Box JW6)
    - 1948-1952 (Box JW7)
    - 1953-1958 (Box JW8)
    - 1959-1962 (Box JW9)
    - 1963-1969 (Box JW10)
    - 1970, 1972, 1976-1980 (Box JW11)
    - 1981-1992, 1980s-1990s, 1996 (Box JW12)
    - JWT company divisions, 1975-1983, 1990-1991 (Box JW13)
    - JWT house advertisements (international), 1917-1985 (Box JW14)
  - Kawasaki Motor Co., 1977-1983
    - 1977-1983 (Box KM1)
  - Kellogg's, 1938-1993
    - 1938-1939, 1952-1953 (some copies from microfilm) (Box KL1)
    - 1955, 1957-1963 (some international) (Box KL1)
    - 1976-1979 (Box KL1)
    - 1980-1993 (Box KL2)
  - Kemper Group, 1972-1988
    - 1972-1979 (Box KG1)
    - 1980-1988 (Box KG2)
  - Kimble Glass, 1948-1950
    - 1948-1950 (Box KI1)
  - Kodak: see Eastman Kodak (Box KI1)
  - Kraft, 1929-1997
    Advertisements for products including Miracle Whip, Velveeta, Philadelphia Cream Cheese, other cheeses, salad dressings, etc. and a number of lesser-known early products are present. Includes many advertisements with recipes and many trade advertisements directed at grocers.
    [See also Oversize Box OV19; Oversize Folders 26-28.]
    - Salad dressings
      - Consumer--Magazine
        - 1941-1963 (Box KR1)
        - 1964-1973 (Box KR2)
        - 1974-1986 (Box KR3)
      - Consumer--Newspaper
        - 1930-1967 (Box KR4)
        - 1968-1977 (Box KR5)
        - 1977-1984 (Box KR6)
      - Trade--Magazine, 1943-1984 (Box KR6)
    - Kraft Mayonnaise
      - Consumer--Magazine
        - 1932-1971 (Box KR7)
        - 1972-1986 (Box KR8)
      - Consumer--Newspaper
        - 1929-1930 (Box KR8)
          Includes 1930s brands: Gelfand, Henard, Easton, Wright.
        - 1931-1933 (Box KR9)
        - 1938-1969 (Box KR10)
        - 1970-1985 (Box KR11)
      - Trade--Magazine, 1930-1931, 1947-1981 (Box KR11)
      - Trade--Newspaper, 1930-1933 (Box KR11)
    - Miracle Whip
      - Consumer--Magazine
        - 1934-1955 (Box KR12)
        - 1956-1992 (Box KR13)
      - Consumer--Newspaper
        - 1933-1936 (Box KR14)
        - 1934-1984 (Box KR15)
      - Trade--Magazine, 1934-1960, 1973, 1980, 1983 (Box KR15)
      - Trade--Newspaper, 1960 (Box KR15)
    - Velveeta
      - Consumer--Magazine
        - 1930-1949 (Box KR16)
        - 1950-1983 (Box KR17)
      - Consumer--Newspaper, 1932-1984 (Box KR18)
      - Trade--Magazine, 1930-1983 (Box KR18)
    - Cheese slices
      - Consumer--Magazine, 1950-1991 (Box KR19)
      - Consumer--Newspaper, 1949-1989 (Box KR20)
      - Trade--Magazine, 1950-1984 (Box KR20)
    - Cracker Barrel
      - Consumer--Magazine, 1954-1985 (Box KR21)
      - Consumer--Newspaper, 1948-1984 (Box KR22)
    - Natural cheeses
      Includes Cheddar, Swiss Colby, Old English, Monterey Jack, Light'n Lively.
      - Consumer--Magazine, 1930-1984 (Box KR23)
        Includes wartime advertisements.
      - Consumer--Newspaper, 1930-1986 (Box KR24)
      - Trade--Magazine, 1932-1978 (Box KR24)
      - Trade--Newspaper, 1931-1973 (Box KR24)
    - Philadelphia Cream Cheese
      - Consumer--Magazine, 1930-1992 (Box KR25)
      - Consumer--Newspaper, 1930-1987 (Box KR26)
      - Insertion schedule, 1930 (Box KR27)
      - Trade--Magazine, 1930-1983 (Box KR27)
    - Miscellaneous cheeses
      - Casino Cheese, 1971-1986 (Box KR27)
      - Cheese Whiz, 1954-1991 (Box KR28)
      - Grated Parmesan Cheese, 1954-1985 (Box KR29)
      - American Cheese, 1930-1953 (Box KR30)
      - Cheese Festivals, 1951-1984 (Box KR30)
      - Combinations of cheeses, 1930-1984 (Box KR31)
    - Combination products
      - International, 1964-1973 (Box KR32)
      - Regional, 1954-1967 (Box KR32)
      - Restaurant, 1950-1974 (Box KR32)
    - Combined products
      - Consumer--Magazine, 1941-1955, 1964-1991 (Box KR33)
      - Consumer--Newspaper, 1930-1981 (Box KR33)
      - Publications, 1964-1967 (Box KR33)
        Includes publications: Culinary Exchange, Vendkraft, Entrees, Food Kraft, Holiday, Menu Merchandizer.
      - Trade--Magazine, 1941-1977 (Box KR33)
    - Various products
      - Dairy products (Box KR34)
        - Cottage cheese, 1938-1968 (Box KR34)
        - Related foods, 1930-1965, 6 folders (Box KR34)
        - Whipped cream cheese, 1959-1964, 2 folders (Box KR34)
      - Miscellaneous foods (Box KR35)
        - Bread products, 1931-1934, 2 folders (Box KR35)
        - Caramels, 1936-1966 (Box KR35)
        - Cheese'n Crackers, 1960-1978 (Box KR35)
        - Dessert products, 1956-1976 (Box KR35)
        - Jellies and preserves, 1957-1966 (Box KR35)
        - Kraco, 1930-1933 (Box KR35)
        - Kragleen, 1944-1955 (Box KR35)
        - Kraystay, 1946-1955 (Box KR35)
        - Marshmallows, 1954-1963 (Box KR36)
        - Orange juice and citrus, 1955-1982 (Box KR36)
        - Oven Melts, 1981-1982 (Box KR36)
        - Potato salad, 1967-1968 (Box KR36)
        - UP'n AT'm, 1972-1973 (Box KR36)
        - Vegemite, 1968-1970 (Box KR36)
      - Miscellaneous prepared foods
        - Cheese spreads, 1933-1983, 4 folders (Box KR37)
        - Flavorizer, 1958-1959 (Box KR37)
        - Instant products, 1959-1964 (Box KR37)
        - Kraft Dinners, 1937-1985 (Box KR37)
        - Kraft Dips, 1968-1983 (Box KR38)
        - Kraft sauces, 1949-1986 (Box KR38)
        - Margarine, 1956-1967 (Box KR38)
        - Miracle sandwich spreads, 1941-1955, 1959-1982 (Box KR38)
        - Shortening, 1953-1971 (Box KR38)
        - Snack cheeses, 1947-1980 (Box KR38)
        - Soup and salad products, 1944-1983 (Box KR38)
    - Food service, 1961-1986 (Box KR39)
      Includes portion control packs.
    - Restaurant and corporate, 1930-1986 (Box KR40)
      Includes America's Jr. Miss program.
    - Grocer's trade, 1930-1987 (Box KR41)
    - Dairy industry, 1930-1981 (Box KR42)
    - Series advertisements, 1930-1969 (Box KR43)
      - About Cows and Things (Box KR43)
      - Buy-Lines (Box KR43)
      - Cheese Fancier's Corner (Box KR43)
      - Creative Cooking (Box KR43)
      - Foods, Facts, and Foibles (Box KR43)
      - Going to Town with Pat Guinan (Box KR43)
      - Good Cooks Column (Box KR43)
      - Happy Food Ideas (Box KR43)
      - Jessie's Notebook (Box KR43)
      - Menuettes (Box KR43)
      - Moos of the Moment (Box KR43)
      - Uncle Ched (Box KR43)
    - Radio and television, 1945-1986 (Box KR44)
    - Sweepstakes, 1957-1984 (Box KR44)
    - Advertisements in foreign languages, 1930-1989 (Box KR45)
      Includes Spanish, French, Hebrew, and German-language advertisements.
    - Kraft Salad Days, 1972-1985 (Box KR46)
    - Pourables--Competitive, 1973-1983 (Box KR47)
    - Consumer--Newspaper, 1985 (Box KR48)
    - Trade, 1985 (Box KR48)
    - Consumer--Magazine, 1986, 2 folders (Box KR48)
    - Consumer--Newspaper, 1986-1987 (Box KR49)
    - Trade, 1986-1987 (Box KR49)
    - Consumer--Magazine, 1987 (Box KR49)
    - Consumer--Magazine, 1988 (Box KR49)
    - Miscellaneous, 1991-1997, 3 folders (Box KR49)
    - Miscellaneous, 1930-1984 (Box KR50)
      Includes billboards and bus cards, caramels, Cheese Festival, cheese spreads, Cheez Whiz, corporate advertising, Cracker Barrel, dairy industry, dessert toppings, dips, grocery trade, Hebrew language advertisements, Kraft Cheese, Kraft Dinners, Kraft Real Mayonnaise, marshmallows, Natural Cheese, Parkay margarine, Philadelphia cream cheese, powdered milk, radio/television, sandwich spreads, soup/salad, Velveeta.
    - Miscellaneous, 1938-1984 (Box KR51)
      Includes cheese slices, combination cheeses, Miracle Whip, orange and citrus juices, sweepstakes.
    - Miscellaneous, 1948-1984 (Box KR52)
      Includes Philadelphia cream cheese and combination products.
    - Miscellaneous, 1930-1980 (Box KR53)
      Includes pourable salad dressings, mayonnaise.
  - Lever Brothers, 1900-1991
    The earliest advertisements are for Lifebuoy Soap. J. Walter Thompson Co. introduced Lux Flakes in 1915 and Lux Toilet Soap in 1925. The early Lux Flakes advertisements employed the talents of fine illustrators. Comic style advertising appeared in the 1930s (Peggy Lux and others). The Lux Toilet Soap campaigns began featuring movie and stage star testimonials in 1927. One noteworthy campaign dates from 1953-1954 when Irving Penn photographed some of Hollywood's most famous stars. The Lever Brothers advertisements for both Lux products also include photographs of car cards (subway and bus posters) from the 1920s. Other Lever Products include Stripe and Close Up toothpastes, Mrs. Butterworth syrup, and Lever 2000 bath soap.
    [See also Oversize Boxes OV20-OV22; Oversize Folder 29.]
    - ca. 1902-1907, Lifebuoy (Box LB1)
    - 1916, Lux (Box LB1)
    - 1916-1918, Lux Flakes (Box LB1)
    - 1917-1918, Insertion schedules (Box LB1)
    - 1923, 1925-1927, Insertion schedules (Box LB2)
    - 1925-1926, Lux Toilet Form (Box LB2)
    - 1920s-1950, Lux Toilet Soap package designs (Box LB2)
    - 1926-1927, Miscellaneous (Box LB3)
    - 1927, Lux (Box LB3)
    - 1927-1930, Lever scrapbook (Box LB4)
    - 1928, Miscellaneous (Box LB5)
    - 1928-1929, Miscellaneous (Box LB6)
    - 1929, Lux Flakes (Box LB7)
    - 1929, Lux Toilet Soap (Box LB8)
    - 1929, Lux Flakes (Box LB8)
    - 1929, Lux Toilet Soap (Box LB9)
    - 1930, Lux Flakes, Lifebuoy, Rinso (Box LB9)
    - 1930, Lux Toilet Soap (Box LB10)
    - 1930, Lux Toilet Soap (Box LB11)
    - 1931, Lux Flakes (Box LB11)
    - 1931, Lux Toilet Soap (Box LB11)
    - 1931, Lux Toilet Soap (Box LB12)
    - 1931, Pears Soap (Box LB12)
    - 1932, Lux Flakes (Box LB12)
    - 1932, Miscellaneous (Box LB13)
    - 1933, Lux Flakes (Box LB14)
    - 1933, Lux Flakes, Lifebuoy, Rinso (Box LB15)
    - 1933, Lux Toilet Soap--Display, layout and tie-ins (Box LB15)
    - 1933, Lux Toilet Soap--Magazine and newspaper (Box LB16)
    - 1933, Lux Toilet Soap--Newspaper (Box LB17)
    - 1933, Pears Soap (Box LB17)
    - 1934, Lux Flakes (Box LB18)
    - 1934, Lux Flakes, Lifebuoy, Rinso (Box LB19)
    - 1934, Lux Toilet Soap (Box LB20)
    - 1935, Lifebuoy, Lux Flakes, Rinso (Box LB21)
    - 1935, Lux Toilet Soap (Box LB22)
    - 1936, Lux Flakes and Toilet Soap (Box LB23)
    - 1936, Lux Flakes and Toilet Soap (Box LB24)
    - 1937, Miscellaneous (Box LB25)
    - 1938, Lifebuoy, Lux Flakes, Rinso, Spry (Box LB26)
    - 1938, Lux Toilet Soap (Box LB27)
    - 1939, Lux Flakes and Toilet Soap (Box LB28)
    - 1939, Lux Flakes and Toilet Soap (Box LB29)
    - 1940, Lux Flakes and Toilet Soap (Box LB30)
    - 1940, New Quick Lux (Box LB31)
    - 1941, Lux Flakes and Toilet Soap (Box LB32)
    - 1941, Lux Toilet Soap (Box LB33)
    - 1941, New Quick Lux (Box LB33)
    - 1942, Lux Flakes and Toilet Soap (Box LB34)
    - 1942, Multiple products scrapbook (Box LB35)
    - 1943, Miscellaneous (Box LB36)
    - 1944, Miscellaneous (Box LB37)
    - 1945, Lever corporate (Box LB38)
    - 1945, Lux Flakes (Box LB38)
    - 1945, Lux Toilet Soap (Box LB39)
    - 1946, Miscellaneous (Box LB40)
    - 1947, Miscellaneous (Box LB41)
    - 1948, Insertion schedule (Box LB42)
    - 1948, Lux Flakes (Box LB42)
    - 1948, Lux radio (Box LB42)
    - 1948, Lux Toilet Soap (Box LB43)
    - 1949, Miscellaneous (Box LB44)
    - 1950-1951, Miscellaneous (Box LB45)
    - 1952-1953, Miscellaneous (Box LB46)
    - 1954-1956, Miscellaneous (Box LB47)
    - 1957-1965, Miscellaneous (Box LB48)
    - 1968-1969, Miscellaneous (Box LB48)
    - 1960s, History of Lux package designs, 1920s-1950s (Box LB48)
    - 1970-1983, Miscellaneous (Box LB49)
    - 1990-1997, Miscellaneous (Box LB49)
  - Liggett and Myers, 1958-1979
    For related materials see the Liggett and Myers Collection.
    [See also Oversize Box OV22; Oversize Folder 29.]
    - 1958-1960 (Box LM1)
    - 1961-1964 (Box LM2)
    - 1965-1972, 1979 (Box LM3)
  - Lilly, Eli: see Eli Lilly (Box LM3)
  - Manufacturers National Bank, 1968-1976
    [See also Oversize Box OV22.]
    - 1968-1970, 1972-1976 (Box MN1)
  - Marsh and McLennan, 1966-1982
    [See also Oversize Box OV22; Oversize Folder 31.]
    - 1966, 1968-1971 (Box ML1)
    - 1972-1982 (Box ML2)
  - Massachusetts Mutual, 1950-1967
    Many of the advertisements contain illustrations by Norman Rockwell.
    - 1950-1959 (Box MA1)
    - 1960-1967 (Box MA2)
  - McDonnell Douglas Corporation, 1952-1992
    [See also Oversize Box OV23; Oversize Folder 33.]
    - 1952-1953 (Box MD1)
    - 1954-1958, 1961-1965 (Box MD2)
    - 1972, 1974, 1977-1979 (Box MD3)
    - 1980-1981 (Box MD4)
    - 1982 (Box MD5)
    - 1983-1984 (Box MD6)
    - 1984 (Box MD7-MD10)
    - 1985 (Box MD11-MD12)
    - 1986 (Box MD13)
    - 1986-1987 (Box MD14)
    - 1987-1988 (Box MD15)
    - 1988 (Box MD16)
    - 1989 (Box MD17-MD18)
    - 1989-1990 (Box MD19)
    - 1990 (Box MD20)
    - 1991-1992 (Box MD21)
  - McGraw Edison, 1956-1968
    [See also Oversize Box OV23.]
    - 1956-1960, 1962-1968 (Box ME1)
  - Mentholathum, 1942-1981
    - 1942-1969 (Box MT1)
    - 1972-1981 (includes insertion schedules) (Box MT2)
  - Mexicana Air, 1984-1994
    - 1984-1994 (Box MX1)
  - Miller Brewing Company (Chicago), 1973-1995
    - General, 1973-1974, 1985-1986 (Box MB1)
    - Löwenbräu Beer, 1985-1995 (Box MB1)
      [See also Oversize Folder 30.]
    - Matilda Bay Wine Cooler, 1987-1989 (Box MB1)
      [See also Oversize Folder 32.]
    - Meister Brau, 1973-1974 (Box MB1)
  - Mink International, 1970-1987
    - 1970-1987 (Box MI1)
      Includes advertisements for SAGA, Blackgama and Canada Majestic.
  - Municipal Bond Investors Assurance (MBIA), 1984-1992
    - 1984-1992 (Box MU1)
  - NATO: see Advertising Council (Box MU1)
  - New Holland Machine Co.: see Sperry-Holland (Box MU1)
  - New York Dress Institute, 1941-1942
    - 1941-1942 (Box NY1)
  - Northeast Airline, 1957-1960
    [See also Oversize Box OV24.]
    - 1957-1959 (Box NE1)
    - 1960 (includes duplicates) (Box NE2)
  - Northern Telecom, 1981-1996
    [See also Oversize Box OV24; Oversize Folder 38.]
    - 1981-1983 (Box NO1)
    - 1983-1985 (Box NO2)
    - 1986-1987 (Box NO3)
    - 1987-1988 (Box NO4)
    - 1989-1990 (Box NO5)
    - 1991-1996 (Box NO6)
  - Northern Trust, 1978-1992
    - 1978-1981 (Box NT1)
    - 1982-1985 (Box NT2)
    - 1986 (Box NT3)
    - 1987 (Box NT4)
    - 1987-1988 (Box NT5)
    - 1989-1992 (Box NT6)
  - Northwestern Mutual, 1948-1997
    - 1948-1960 (Box NM1)
    - 1961-1965 (Box NM2)
    - 1966-1972 (Box NM3)
    - 1977, 1980-1991, 1996-1997 (Box NM4)
  - Nurse recruitment: see Advertising Council (Box NM4)
  - Orkin, 1983-1996
    [See also Oversize Box OV24; Oversize Folder 37.]
    - 1983-1984, 1986-1996 (Box OR1)
  - Oscar Mayer and Co., 1960-1997
    - 1960-1964 (Box OM1)
    - 1965-1978 (Box OM2)
    - 1979-1983 (Box OM3)
    - 1984-1997 (Box OM4)
  - Owen-Illinois Glass Co., 1944-1961
    - 1944 (Box OI1)
    - 1945 (Box OI2)
    - 1946 (Box OI3)
    - 1947 (Box OI4)
    - 1948 (Box OI5)
    - 1949 (Box OI6)
    - 1950 (Box OI7)
    - 1951-1952 (Box OI8)
    - 1953 (Box OI9)
    - 1954 (Box OI10)
    - 1955 (Box OI11)
    - 1956 (Box OI12)
    - 1957-1958 (Box OI13)
    - 1959-1961 (Box OI14)
  - Pan American World Airways, 1942-1974
    Contains advertisements prepared for both U.S. and international consumers and includes the introduction of jet passenger travel. Cargo advertising also can be found.
    See also Oversize Folder 39.
    - Magazine, 1942-1943 (Box PA1)
    - Newspaper, 1942-1947 (Box PA2)
    - Magazine, 1944-1946 (Box PA3)
    - Magazine, 1947-1948 (Box PA4)
    - Newspaper, 1948 (Box PA5)
    - Magazine, 1949 (Box PA6)
    - Newspaper, 1949 (Box PA7)
    - Magazine, 1950 (Box PA8)
    - Newspaper, 1950 (Box PA9)
    - Newspaper, 1951-1952 (Box PA10)
    - Magazine, 1952-1953 (Box PA11)
    - Newspaper, 1953 (Box PA12)
    - Magazine, 1954 (Box PA13)
    - Newspaper, 1954 (Box PA14)
    - Newspaper, 1954-1955 (Box PA15)
    - Newspaper 1955 (Box PA16)
    - Newspaper, 1955 (Box PA17)
    - Magazine, 1955 (Box PA18)
    - Magazine, 1956 (Box PA19)
    - Newspaper, 1956 (Box PA20)
    - Newspaper, 1956-1957 (Box PA21)
    - Magazine, 1957 (Box PA22)
    - Magazine, 1958-1960 (also Canada 1959-1961) (Box PA23)
    - Newspaper, 1958-1959 (Box PA24)
    - Newspaper, 1959-1960 (Box PA25)
    - Newspaper, 1960 (Box PA26)
    - Outdoor proof book, 1960 (Box PA27)
    - Magazine, 1961 (Box PA28)
    - Magazine, 1961 (Box PA29)
    - Newspaper, 1961 (Box PA30)
    - Magazine, 1962 (Box PA31-PA32)
    - Newspaper, 1962 (Box PA33-PA34)
    - Magazine, 1963 (Box PA35-PA36)
    - Newspaper, 1963 (Box PA37-PA38)
    - Magazine, 1964 (Box PA39-PA40)
    - Newspaper, 1964 (Box PA41-PA43)
    - Magazine, 1965 (Box PA44-PA48)
    - Newspaper, 1969 (Box PA49-PA52)
    - Magazine and outdoor, 1966 (Box PA53-PA55)
    - Magazine, 1966 (Box PA56-PA57)
    - Newspaper, 1966 (Box PA58-PA61)
    - Magazine, 1967 (Box PA62-PA67)
    - Magazine (Tokyo Office), 1967 (Box PA68)
    - Magazine and outdoor, 1967 (Box PA69-PA71)
    - Newspaper, 1967 (Box PA72-PA74)
    - Magazine, 1967 (Box PA75)
    - Magazine and outdoor, 1968 (Box PA76-PA77)
    - Newspaper, 1968-1969 (Box PA78)
    - Magazine, 1969 (Box PA79-PA82)
    - Newspaper, 1969-1971 (Box PA83)
    - Magazine, 1970 (Box PA84)
    - Magazine, 1971-1974 (Box PA85)
  - Parker Pen, 1931-1980
    - 1931, 1942-1955 (Box PR1)
    - 1969-1972 (Box PR2)
    - 1973-1980 (Box PR3)
  - Partnership for a Drug-Free America: see Advertising Council (Box PR3)
  - Phillips Petroleum Co., 1962-1972
    [See also Oversize Box OV24; Oversize Folder 40.]
    - 1962-1964 (Box PH1)
    - 1965-1972 (Box PH2)
  - Premier Cruise Lines, 1990-1992
    - 1990-1991 (Box PC1)
    - 1991-1992 (Box PC2)
  - Purolator, 1949-1964
    [See also Oversize Folder 40.]
    - 1949-1950 (Box PU1)
    - 1951-1953 (Box PU2)
    - 1954-1964 (Box PU3)
  - Quaker Oats, 1917-1994
    For related materials see the J. Walter Thompson Co. Chicago Office, Quaker Oats Account Files, 1945-1965.
    - 1917-1925, 1928, 1953-1956 (Box QO1)
    - 1957-1960 (Box QO2)
    - 1961-1962 (Box QO3)
    - 1963-1965 (Box QO4)
    - 1966-1969 (Box QO5)
    - 1970-1974 (Box QO6)
    - 1975-1977 (Box QO7)
    - 1978-1980 (Box QO8)
    - 1981-1983 (Box QO9)
    - 1986-1994 (Box QO10)
  - RCA (Radio Corporation of America), 1917-1976
    In addition to consumer products, advertisements for NBC (The National Broadcasting Company) programs can be found in this group.
    [See also Oversize Box OV25.]
    - 1917-1918 (Box RC1)
      - Supremacy advertisements, Victrola (Box RC1)
    - 1943
      - Communications (Box RC1)
      - Insertion schedules (Box RC1)
      - Institutional (Box RC1)
      - Laboratories (Box RC1)
      - NBC (National Broadcasting Company) (Box RC1)
      - Public service (Box RC1)
      - Radio/Marine (Box RC1)
      - RCA Victor programs (Box RC1)
      - Victor records (Box RC1)
    - 1944 (Box RC2)
      - Cincinnati (Box RC2)